Guide to the Robert A. Caro Archive [DATE]–2021 MS 3203
New-York Historical Society
Robert A. Caro papers
[DATE]–2021
New-York Historical Society
Caro, Robert A.
MS 3203
[100?] Linear feet in # record cartons, # flat boxes, # scrapbooks,...
Papers of Pulitzer Prize and National Book Award winner Robert A. Caro, author of The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York (1974), the seminal study on the uses and abuses of political power, and of The Years of Lyndon Johnson (1982–ongoing), his massively-detailed biography of the 36th President of the United States. In addition to the copious research and interview notes, manuscript and typed drafts, and galley proofs documenting the creation of these works, the collection includes material from Caro's earliest efforts, when he edited and contributed to his high school and college newspapers (Horace Mann, class of 1953; Princeton, class of 1957). Also present are files from Caro's years as a newspaper reporter for Newsday, where his investigations exposed, among other scandals, the fraudulent dealings of real estate brokers who duped retirees into buying worthless land by mail. A series of scrapbooks details Caro's working life through book reviews, profiles, interviews, photographs, awards, and ephemera.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchase, Robert A. Caro, Inc., 2020 [USING ANY PARTICULAR FUNDS THAT MUST BE MENTIONED?]
Arrangement
The Robert A. Caro Archive is organized in twelve series:
Series I.
Early writings, 1952-1955
Series II.
Newsday reportage, [DATE-DATE]
Series III.
The Power Broker: Robert Moses and the Fall of New York (published 1974), [1966–1973?]
Series IV.
The Years of Lyndon Johnson: The Path to Power (published 1982), [DATE-DATE]
Series V.
The Years of Lyndon Johnson: Means of Ascent (published 1990), [DATE-DATE]
Series VI.
The Years of Lyndon Johnson: Master of the Senate (published 2002), [DATE-DATE]
Series VII.
The Years of Lyndon Johnson: The Passage of Power (published 2012), [DATE-DATE]
[Series VIII.]
[The Years of Lyndon Johnson: final volume (forthcoming), [DATE-DATE]
Series IX.
Working: Researching, Interviewing, Writing (published 2019), [DATE-DATE]
Series X.
Other writings, [DATE-DATE]
Series XI.
Scrapbooks, 1952-2021 (bulk, 1974-2020)
Series XII.
Objects, [DATE-DATE]
Biographical / Historical
TBD
Scope and Contents
TBD
Drafts (documents); Ephemera.; Galley proofs.; Interviews.; Letters (correspondence); Newspaper clippings.; Notebooks.; Pamphlets.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Promotional materials.; Research (documents); Scrapbooks.; Biographers -- United States.; City planners.; Investigative reporting.; Journalism.; Political power.; Public works -- New York (State) -- New York.; Reporters and reporting -- United States.; Caro, Ina; Caro, Robert A. -- Years of Lyndon Johnson.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Moses, Robert, 1888-1981; Horace Mann School (New York, N.Y.); Princeton University
- Series I. Early writings, 1952-1955
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains pieces written by Caro during his high school and college years. A scrapbook holds scattered issues of the "Horace Mann Record" his Bronx high school newspaper, which he edited, for 1952-1953. The issue of May 12, 1952 announces his appointment as editor. Note also the issue of December 8, 1952 (vol. XLVI, no. 11), which exists in English and Russian-language editions; Caro produced the latter and sent 10,000 copies to students in the USSR. At Princeton, Caro contributed to the "Daily Princetonian," of which he was also managing editor. Series I includes a number of his "Ivy Inklings" columns, which covered matches of Princeton's athletic teams, as well as profiles of faculty (see the series "Princeton's Great Lecturers" March 24-31, 1955) and fellow students ("Senior Weds, Ending Car and Cooking Worries," September 28, 1954).
  Arrangement
  The material in Series I is in chronological order, with minor deviations.
  - "Robert A. Caro. The Horace Mann record. Horace Mann School, 1952" (Scrapbook [A]), 1952-1953 (Box [XI-01])
    Contains scattered issues of The Horace Mann Record from when Caro was its editor; see May 12, 1952 issue for headline of his appointment and photo. Note the discrepancies in volume numbering.
    [Numbers in brackets represent the pages of the scrapbook. Pages containing multiple items are marked "a," "b," etc.]
    [01] Vol. XLV, No. 19 (March 3, 1952)
    [02] Vol. XLV, No. 28 (May 12, 1952)
    [03] Vol. XLI [sic; XLVI], No. 1 (September 18, 1952)
    [04] Vol. XLI [sic; XLVI], No. 2 (September 29, 1952)
    [05] Vol. XLI [sic; XLVI], No. 3 (October 6, 1952) [copy 1]
    [06] Vol. XLVI, No. 4 (October 13, 1952)
    [07] Vol. XLVI, No. 5 (October 20, 1952)
    [08] Vol. XLVI, No. 6 (October 27, 1952)
    [09] Vol. XLVI, No. 7 (November 3, 1952)
    [10] Vol. XLVI, No. 8 (November 10, 1952)
    [11] Vol. XLVI, No. 9 (November 17, 1952)
    [12] Vol. XLVI, No. 10 (November 10 [sic], 1952)
    [13a] Vol. XLVI, No. 11 (December 8, 1952). Translation for the Russian edition
    [13b] Vol. XLVI, No. 11 (December 8, 1952). Russian edition]
    [14] Two photos of editorial staff; one definitely includes Caro
    [15] [blank]
    [16] Vol. XLVI, No. 12 (December 8, 1952)
    [17a] Vol. XLVI, No. 13 (December 17, 1952)
    [17b] Letter from Mitchell Gratwick, principal, thanking Caro for his work on Christmas issue
    [18] Vol. XLVI, No. 14 (January 12, 1953)
    [19] Vol. XLVI, No. 15 (January 19, 1953)
    [20] Vol. XLVI, No. 16 (February 9, 1953)
    [21] Vol. XLVI, No. 17 (February 16, 1953)
    [22] Program / scorecard, "Horace Mann vs. Riverdale Annual Polio Fund Basketball Game," February 27, 1953 [2 copies]
    [23] Vol. XLVI, No. 19 (February 27, 1953)
    [24] Vol. XLVI, No. 22 (March 13, 1953)
    [25] Vol. XLVI, No. 24 (April 1, 1953). April Fool's Day Issue [2 copies]
    [26] Vol. XLVI, No. 25 (April 7, 1953)
    [27] Vol. XLVI, No. 26 (April 13, 1953)
    [28] Vol. XLVI, No. 27 (April 20, 1953)
    [29] Vol. XLVI, No. 28 (April 23, 1953)
    [30] Vol. XLVI, No. 29 (April 27, 1953)
    [31] Vol. XLVI, No. 30 (May 3, 1953)
    [32] "Horace Mann Parents Association Field Day Baseball and Tennis Programs P. A. Handbook Theatre Playbill," May 8, 1953 [complete copy]
    [33] "Horace Mann Parents Association Field Day Baseball and Tennis Programs P. A. Handbook Theatre Playbill," May 8, 1953 [partial copy]
    [34] Vol. XLVI, No. 32 (May 11, 1953)
    [35] Vol. XLVI, No. 33 (May 18, 1953)
    [36] Vol. XLVI, No. 34 (May 22, 1953)
    [37a] "Columbia Scholastic Press Association Award," March 13, 1953
    [37b] "Horace Mann Record Style Sheet"
    [38] Vol. XLI [sic; XLVI], No. 3 (October 6, 1952) [copy 2]
    [39] Clipping from the Daily Princetonian, November 18, 1953: "The Daily Princetonian takes pleasure in announcing the election of Robert A. Caro '57 of New York City, A. Slade Mills '56 of Morristown, N.J., and William E. Tangney '57 of Quincy, Mass., to the posts of Assistant Editors; and of David E. Sosin '57 to the Photographic Staff."
    [40] The Inter-School News, Vol. IV, No. 4 (May 1952)
  - Daily Princetonian Stories, 1954-1955 (Box [XI-01], Enclosure 1)
    Loose clippings, mostly of Caro's "Ivy Inklings" sports column; originally housed in an envelope marked "Daily Princetonian Stories, 1954–1955" and placed inside the front cover of the scrapbook embossed "Robert A. Caro. The Horace Mann record. Horace Mann School, 1952." An earlier clipping, dated November 18, 1953, announcing Caro's appointment as assistant editor, appears near the end of the Horace Mann scrapbook. And a photocopy of a later piece, "Morris Bucks for Winning Touchdown As Penn Goal-Line Stands Slow Tigers," from the issue of October 10, 1955, appears in Scrapbook [24] (see Series XI).
    Complete, digitized issues of The Daily Princetonian, 1876–2015, are available online at theprince.princeton.edu.
    1954 Sep. 22: "Guarantee 'Tug' Rope. Frosh, Sophs Prepare for Annual 'Spree'."
    1954 Sep. 28: "Senior Weds, Ending Car and Cooking Worries."
    1954 Sep. 30: "'McCarthyism' Debate Splits Wisconsin Campus. Arguments Rage As 'Merry Men' Distribute Buttons And Posters."
    1954 Oct. 14: "Soph Duo at Tackle. Penn Game Starters to Open Against Brown."
    1954 Oct. 15: "Brown, With Backfield in Shape, Favored Over Young Tiger Eleven" (fragment).
    1954 Oct. 18: "Martin Injured. Brown Rally Trips Tigers, 21-20."
    1954 Oct. 29: "Soph Linemen: Key to Princeton's Grid Future? Harder, Melges, Bowman Battling For Tackle Posts."
    1954 Nov. 03: "Ivy Inklings. The touch football games are still going strong.. ."
    1954 Nov. 04: "Ivy Inklings. On the first night of practice Cappy Cappon yelled.. ."
    1954 Nov. 09: "Speaks on Legal Career. Vanderbilt Urges Change In Judicial Nominations."
    1954 Nov. 10: "Intime Leading Lady. Actress Juggles Home, Theatre."
    1954 Nov. 16: "Comparable To '46 Penn Game; Tiger Win Adds To Upset List."
    1954 Nov. 17: "Budgetary Revision Needed. Palmer Asks Changes in France" (fragment).
    1954 Nov. 23: "Haabestad Set For Big Year. Cappon Working with All-Veteran Quintet As Team Enters Third Week of Practice."
    1954 Nov. 30: "Davidson Shots Click. Hoopsters Impressive In Three Scrimmages."
    1954 Dec. 08: "Ivy Inklings. The big news in basketball circles at this stage of the season.. ."
    1954 Dec. 09: "Batt's Loss Costly. Tiger Five Drops Opener, 85-74" (fragment).
    1955 Feb. 02: "Architecture Tour, Talks to Sophs Will Initiate 1955 Bicker Tonight (fragment).
    1955 Feb. 03: "Ivy Inklings. To the sportswriters who follow the season-changing swirl of sports.. ."
    1955 Feb. 04: "Clark Urges Sincerity; Club Lists Average 530. Five Clubs to Visit Over 650 Eligibles."
    1955 Feb. 07: "Deep Spiritual Rebirth Urged by Voice Official."
    1955 Feb. 09: "As Tigers Roll, Cagers Trounce Cornell In Crucial Game, 74-47."
    1955 Feb. 14: "Tiger Skaters Blank Bulldogs, 2-0; Cagers Split Pair of League Games; Top Brown, 57-55; Lose To Harvard."
    1955 Feb. 15: "Ivy Inklings. A disgusted Cappy Cappon gave the varsity a tongue-lashing yesterday."
    1955 Feb. 16: "Game Tonight 'Must' For Tigers. Forte Leads Columbia Against Cagers" (fragment).
    1955 Feb. 17: "Cagers Rally to Edge Columbia, 53-52; Easton, Batt Lead Princeton Comeback; With Four Fouls, Batt Holds Thomas."
    1955 Feb. 22: "Ivy Inklings. The hours of practice.. ." (fragment).
    1955 Feb. 28: "Batt's Clutch Basket Kills Cornell, 65-62; Tigers' Title Hopes Rise as Penn Loses."
    1955 Mar. 01: "Ivy Inklings. The wrestling team managed to fill a potential gap in the 167-pound division.. ."
    1955 Mar. 02: "Haabestad—Forte To Duel; Tiger 'Iron Men' to Meet Columbia Cagers Tonight" (fragment).
    1955 Mar. 03: "Columbia Wins, 65-58, In Second Half Surge."
    1955 Mar. 07: "Brilliant Teamwork Crushes Penn As Tiger Cagers Tighten Ivy Race" (fragment).
    1955 Mar. 08: "Tigers Smash Brown Five, 58-39, Will Meet Lions For NCAA Berth; Lions Edge Penn By 73-71 Margin."
    1955 Mar. 09: "Nassau Veterans Meet Lion Sophs Tonight in Ivy Loop Playoff Game; Columbia to Count on Forte's Shooting."
    1955 Mar. 09: "Ivy Inklings. As far as Hal Haabestad, Dick Batt and John Easton are concerned.. ."
    1955 Mar. 10: "Tiger 'Iron Men' Rout Lions, 86-69, To Capture Ivy Basketball Crown; Princeton to Battle La Salle in NCAA."
    1955 Mar. 11: David and GOLiAth; Hoopsters Meet LaSalle In NCAA Opener Tonight."
    1955 Mar. 14: "Tired Tigers End Season; Cagers Lose to LaSalle and Villanova."
    1955 Mar. 22: "Ivy Inklings. The true test of any ballplayer is what he can do in the clutch."
    1955 Mar. 24: "Today's Great Lecturers: The Latest Link In the Princeton Educational Tradition."
    1955 Mar. 25: "Princeton's Great Lecturers—II. Wade, Mason, Wilson Creating New Link in Tradition."
    1955 Mar. 29: "Princeton's Great Lecturers—III. Strayer, Harbison, Craig Follow History Department's Traditions."
    1955 Mar. 30: "Princeton's Great Lecturers—IV. Two Outstanding Men in Economics, Philosophy; Baumol Livens Economics 313; Sincerity Of Tumin Apparent."
    1955 Mar. 31: "Princeton's Great Lecturers—V. Thomas, Ashby, Ramsey Molded Religion Tradition in Ten Years."
    1955 Apr. 13: "Ivy Inklings. This being the time of the year when sportswriters' thoughts lightly turn to baseball predictions.. ."
    1955 Apr. 21: "'Remarkable Experiences'; Alumnus Praises Career in U.S. Foreign Service."
    1955 Apr. 25: "Secret Research Team Here Aided H-Bomb Development; Project Matterhorn Headed by Wheeler."
    1955 Apr. 26: "Wheeler Tells Why 'Matterhorn' Was Moved Here From Los Alamos; Atmosphere Called Reason For Change."
    1955 Apr. 28: "Ivy Inklings. Attendance at Ivy League athletic events.. ."
    1955 May 03: "The Philadelphia Story—I. Princeton Grad Entering Duel for GOP's Support."
    1955 May 04: "The Philadelphia Story—II. Longstreth '41 Embarks On Lightning Campaign."
    1955 May 11: "$2,000,000 in Expansion Projected Here by ETS."
    1955 May 12: "Ivy Inklings. The dictates of the Ivy League restrict Charlie Caldwell's springtime gridiron activities.. ."
    1955 May 18: "Longstreth Wins GOP Primary in Philadelphia."
    1955 May 20: "Longstreth Ready for All-Out Drive."
    1955 May 30: "Joint Panels Are Planned For Reunion."
- Series II. Newsday reportage
  TBD
  - Subseries II.A. Newsday research files [cabinet 2 / drawer 2]
    Drawer labeled "Novel: Rough draft; Home News: Dollar dilemma; Newsday: Files for 'Misery Acres'." (original drawer label from file cabinet 2 is in Box P51)
    Larry's survey notes...
    Cabinet 2, drawer 2, box P53: Typescript draft(s?) of a novel "News Man." 24 folders from Newsday era: Most labeled as "Land Scandals" and others likely related ("Misery Acres," "Auerbach Inc.", "Crooks," etc.). Original documents compiled by Caro during his research, letters to him related to the scandals, Caro's notes, including at least one off the record interview (with Claude Pepper of Florida). Transcript of taped interview between Caro and Dory Auerbach.
    Cabinet 2, drawer 2, box P54: 14 folders continued from above re: land scandals, including Florida and Arizona/Southwest
    - LAND SCANDALS—STORY FILE, 1963 (Box P53, Folder 1)
      Newsday clippings.
    - LAND SCANDALS—FIRST AMERICA, 1962-1963 (Box P53, Folder 1)
      Clippings, correspondence, brochures (e.g., "Florida's New Smyrna Acres").
    - MITCHEL—Used Already & Background, 1961-1962 (Box P53, Folder 2)
    - AUERBACH, INC., 1962-1963 (Box P53, Folder 3)
      Includes typescript of "Conversation between Dory Auerbach, David Randell, and Robert Caro of Newsday, Garden City, New York, November 28, 1962."
    - Suffolk—Recent Clips, 1963-1964 (Box P53, Folder 4)
    - Suffolk—Planning, 1963-1964 (Box P53, Folder 4)
    - Suffolk—New Series, 1963 (Box P53, Folder 4)
    - [untitled], 1964 (Box P53, Folder 4)
      Mostly typed notes dealing with Robert Moses and Al Smith.
    - Promotion, 1963 (Box P53, Folder 4)
    - Land Scandals, 1963-1964 (Box P53, Folder 5)
    - MISERY ACRES—ALL NEW (after 12/22/63), 1963 (Box P53, Folder 5)
    - LAND SCANDALS—ADLER, 1963 (Box P53, Folder 5)
    - LAND SCANDALS—FUTURE CHECKS, 1963-1964 (Box P53, Folder 6)
    - CROOKS, 1961-1962 (Box P53, Folder 6)
    - LAND SCANDALS—Post-Series, 1962-1963 (Box P53, Folder 6)
    - LAND SCANDALS—POST-SERIES II, 1963 (Box P53, Folder 6)
    - LAND SCANDALS—SENATE COMMITTEE (Box P53, Folder 7)
    - LAND SCANDALS—FLA. GOVT. CONSPIRACY, 1962 (Box P53, Folder 7)
    - LAND SCANDALS—NEW FLORIDA (Box P53, Folder 7)
    - LAND SCANDALS—SMATHERS & HOFFA, 1963-1964 (Box P53, Folder 7)
    - LAND SCANDALS—PREPARING FOR SERIES II, 1959-1963 (Box P53, Folder 7)
    - LAND SCANDALS—FINAL SENATE HEARINGS, 1964 (Box P53, Folder 8)
    - LAND SCANDALS—AMERICAN REALTY & PETROLEUM CO., 1962-1963 (Box P53, Folder 9)
    - AR&P [American Realty & Petroleum Co.], 1963 (Box P53, Folder 10)
    - LAND SCANDALS—FOREIGN, 1960-1963 (Box P53, Folder 10)
    - LAND SCANDALS—LAWS, 1962-1963 (Box P53, Folder 11)
    - LAND SCANDALS—SUBCOMMITTEE FILES, 1964 (Box P53, Folder 12)
    - LAND SCANDALS—SUOZZI, 1961-1962 (Box P53, Folder 12)
    - Great Southwestern Land Co., Inc., 1962-1963 (Box P54, Folder 1)
    - GULF AMERICAN [Gulf American Land Corporation], 1962-1964 (Box P54, Folder 1)
    - LAND SCANDALS—FLORIDA, 1957-1963 (Box P54, Folder 2)
    - LAND SCANDALS—COLLIER, 1957-1963 (Box P54, Folder 3)
    - LAND SCANDALS—FLA. SERIES, 1956-1963 (Box P54, Folder 4)
    - ALBANY, 1963 (Box P54, Folder 5)
    - SPURGEON PICKERING, 1962 (Box P54, Folder 5)
    - MINOR FLORIDA & SMATHERS, 1963 (Box P54, Folder 5)
    - HARBOUR HEIGHTS, 1962-1964 (Box P54, Folder 5)
    - LAND SCANDALS—Talley in Washington, 1962-1964 (Box P54, Folder 6)
    - LAND SCANDALS—INDIVIDUALS, Letters From, 1963 (Box P54, Folder 6)
    - LAND SCANDALS—ARIZONA & OVERALL, 1961-1964 (Box P54, Folder 7)
  - Subseries II.B. Newsday research files [cabinet 2 / drawer 3]
    Drawer labeled "Newsday: Files for Suffolk: Sick Giant; Waldemar, Keating & World's Fair '64." On back of label: "Novel-Rough." (original drawer label from file cabinet 2 is in Box P51)
    WALDEMAR = Waldemar Medical Research Foundation, Inc. / Waldemar Cancer Research and Prevention Center, Woodbury, Long Island
    Cabinet 2, drawer 3, box P55: 23 folders all with main heading of "Suffolk." Probably for different articles. Material here on taxes, LILCO, a bridge, unemployment, transportation, etc. Caro's notes from sources (some gathered in "typed notes" folder). Clippings with the articles he wrote. Many original documents.
    Cabinet 2, drawer 3, box P56: 26 folders. Most are on topic of "Waldemar," a medical research foundation: Clips of Caro's stories, background documents, etc. Folder on "Suit" includes a thick memo from Caro to Andy Hughes (attorney?) detailing his work on the topic. 3 more Suffolk folders (continuing from above), 3 folders on the 1964 World's Fair (appears to have something to do with finances and executive expenses). 2 folders on Ken Keating 1964 campaign for senator and Caro's articles.
    - SUFFOLK: BRIDGE STORY FILE, 1963-1965 (Box P54, Folder 8)
    - SUFFOLK—PERSONAL, 1963-1965 (Box P54, Folder 8)
    - SUFFOLK—LILCO [Long Island Lighting Company], 1962-1963 (Box P54, Folder 8)
    - SUFFOLK—HUNTINGTON, 1962-1963 (Box P54, Folder 9)
    - Bridge Campaign—Typed, 1963-1964 (Box P54, Folder 9)
    - SUFFOLK—BABYLON, 1963-1964 (Box P54, Folder 9)
    - SUFFOLK: BRIDGE CAMPAIGN, 1963-1965 (Box P54, Folder 10)
    - Suffolk—Tax Map, 1962-1964 (Box P54, Folder 10)
    - SUFFOLK—UNEMPLOYMENT & DEFENSE, 1962-1963 (Box P54, Folder 11)
    - SUFFOLK—TYPED NOTES, 1963 (Box P54, Folder 11)
    - SUFFOLK—Transportation: Congestion, RR, Airport, Rds, 1963 (Box P54, Folder 11)
    - SUFFOLK—STATISTICS, 1962-1963 (Box P54, Folder 12)
    - SUFFOLK: BRIDGE—CONNECTICUT, 1962-1963 (Box P54, Folder 12)
    - SUFFOLK: BRIDGE—RHODE ISLAND, 1962-1964 (Box P54, Folder 12)
    - SUFFOLK: LI ECONOMY ROUND-UP, OCT., 1964, 1963-1964 (Box P55, Folder 1)
    - SUFFOLK: LI ECONOMY ROUND-UP, APR., 1965 (Box P55, Folder 1)
    - SUFFOLK: STORY FILE, 1963-1964 (Box P55, Folder 1)
    - SUFFOLK—AFTER TURNOVER, 1965 (Box P55, Folder 1)
    - SUFFOLK—EAST END & BRIDGE, 1958-1964 (Box P55, Folder 1)
    - SUFFOLK—LURING INDUSTRY, 1963 (Box P55, Folder 2)
    - SUFFOLK—WATER & SEWERS (Box P55, Folder 2)
    - Suffolk—Promotion, 1963 (Box P55, Folder 2)
    - SUFFOLK—MONMOUTH, 1958-1962 (Box P55, Folder 2)
    - WALDEMAR—PERSONAL, 1964 (Box P55, Folder 3)
    - WALDEMAR—INACTIVE MEMOS & LEADS, 1963-1964 (Box P55, Folder 3)
    - WALDEMAR: DUPES & UNUSABLE STUFF, 1963-1964 (Box P55, Folder 3)
    - WALDEMAR: FINANCES—RADGLO, 1959-1962 (Box P55, Folder 3)
    - WALDEMAR: JULIA, 1963 (Box P55, Folder 4)
      Julia = Julia M. Lampkin-Hibbard, Ph.D., Director, Cancer Research, Applied Research Laboratories of Florida, Inc.
    - WALDEMAR: TWO REPORTS (Box P55, Folder 4)
    - WALDEMAR: PROMOTION, 1964-1965 (Box P55, Folder 4)
    - WALDEMAR—INCORPORATION CERTIFICATE, 1954-1964 (Box P55, Folder 4)
    - WALDEMAR: FINANCES—1962 & ALL STATE, 1955-1964 (Box P55, Folder 4)
    - WALDEMAR: FINANCES—1963 (Box P55, Folder 5)
    - WALDEMAR—STORY FILE, 1964 (Box P55, Folder 5)
    - WALDEMAR: FINANCES—1964 (Box P55, Folder 5)
    - WALDEMAR—ALL PRINTED STUFF, 1958-1964 (Box P55, Folder 6)
    - WALDEMAR: FUTURE CHECKS, 1962-1964 (Box P55, Folder 7)
    - WALDEMAR—COMMUNIST, 1964-1965 (Box P55, Folder 7)
    - WALDEMAR—LIVE STUFF, 1960-1964 (Box P55, Folder 7)
    - WALDEMAR—SUIT, 1961-1965 (Box P55, Folder 8)
    - WALDEMAR—ALL GRAND JURY & 'DISCOVERY', 1964 (Box P55, Folder 9)
    - WORLD'S FAIR: TYPED NOTES, 1963-1968 (Box P55, Folder 9)
    - WF: ALL PRINTED STUFF, 1959-1964 (Box P55, Folder 10)
    - WORLD'S FAIR: INSURANCE & SPARGO, 1946, 1958-1968 (Box P55, Folder 10)
    - SUFFOLK—APARTMENTS, undated (Box P55, Folder 10)
    - SUFFOLK—FUTURE CHECKS, 1929, 1962-1965 (Box P55, Folder 11)
    - SUFFOLK—MAPPING PROGRAM & ALL SUPES [Board of Supervisors], 1960-1964 (Box P55, Folder 11)
    - KEATING—NOTES & STORIES [Keating = U.S. Senator Kenneth B. Keating], 1964 (Box P55, Folder 11)
    - KEATING—ALL PRINTED STUFF [Keating = U.S. Senator Kenneth B. Keating], 1964 (Box P55, Folder 11)
  - Subseries II.#. Newsday research files
    [Trunk 3] Power Broker [crossed out] Newsday (MSS material) (4 of 5 boxes)
    These contents all appear to relate to Caro's Newsday years. Many folders on topics: insecticides, franchises, Cahn-Nickerson jukebox riot, Speno land case, anatomy of a burglary. Pile of loose documents: Clippings, photostats/Thermofax of police reports, etc., typed notes. Useful for exhibition perhaps: many reprints of Caro's Misery Acres articles in Newsday.
    - L: SPENO, 1962-1965 (Box P12, Folder 1)
    - [Moreland Commission], 1964 (Box P12, Folder 1)
    - CAHN-NICKERSON JUKEBOX RIOT, 1961-1965 (Box P12, Folder 1)
    - AIR SAFETY, 1962 (Box P12, Folder 1)
    - Franchises [2 folders in 1], 1957-1965 (Box P12, Folder 2)
    - BI-COUNTY PLANNING (NOTES), undated (Box P12, Folder 3)
    - ANATOMY OF A $9 BURGLARY, undated (Box P12, Folder 3)
    - SIBEN, [1965] (Box P12, Folder 3)
      Research and notes for Caro's Newsday piece, "The Legal Mogul, Or, How a Struggling Young Law Student Became Sidney R. Siben, Esq." Includes four copies of the published article, which ran on April 24, 1965.
    - Personal, 1963 (Box P12, Folder 3)
    - INSECTICIDES, 1960-1962 (Box P13, Folder 4)
      Includes various governmental pamphlets and publications, such as a comic book issued by the Food and Drug Administration, "Dennis the Menace Takes a Poke at Poison" (1961).
    - INSECTICIDES II, 1962 (Box P12, Folder 5)
      Includes clippings of Caro's five-part series "Pesticides: The Hidden Poisons," Newsday, August 20-24, 1962.
    - HOW TO SUCCEED, 1965 (Box P12, Folder 5)
      Advertisements for self-help scams.
    - "LI in '65", 1964 (Box P12, Folder 5)
      Research for and clippings of Caro's "Forecast: The Island," Newsday, December 26, 1964.
    - LI's MADISON AVENUE, 1964 (Box P12, Folder 5)
    - L: THE BRACKENS, 1961-1962 (Box P12, Folder 6)
    - L: ALL PUBLIC STATEMENTS & PRESS CONFERENCES, [1965] (Box P12, Folder 6)
    - FIRESTER, undated (Box P12, Folder 6)
    - L: MELI & STONE, [1963-1965] (Box P12, Folder 6)
    - L: GENERAL, undated (Box P12, Folder 6)
    - L: MONTER TRACT, undated (Box P12, Folder 6)
    - "Misery Acres" reprints [without supplement], 1963 (Box P12, Folder 7)
    - "Misery Acres" reprints [with supplement], 1963 (Box P12, Folder 8)
    - "Misery Acres: Chapter II" reprints [folder 1 of 2], 1963 (Box P12, Folder 9)
    - "Misery Acres: Chapter II" reprints [folder 2 of 2], 1963 (Box P12, Folder 10)